Guide to the Eugene Winick Papers Relating to Eugene O'Neill
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Eugene Winick papers relating to Eugene O'Neill
1923-1949
YCAL MSS 758
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.13
(8 boxes)
The Eugene Winick papers relating to Eugene O'Neill consist of correspondence and other papers dating from the mid 1920s through late 1940s. There is correspondence addressed to Eugene and Carlotta O'Neill from publishers, literary agents, law firms, and individuals, with large files for the literary agency, Richard J. Madden Play Company, Random House, Theatre Guild, and the law firm of Harry Weinberger. There are also subject folders for "foreign letters" and "requests" relating to permissions, translations, critical works and reception, research inquiries, financial matters, invitations, and other matters. Other papers consist chiefly of financial records, including income tax related material for the years from 1937 through 1948, investment reports, and royalty statements from Dramatists Play Service, Random House, and the Richard J. Madden Play Company.
Winick, Eugene
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Eugene Winick, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 8: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Eugene O'Neill (1888-1953)
For a chronology on Eugene O'Neill and Carlotta Monterey O'Neill (1888-1970), see the Eugene O'Neill Papers (YCAL MSS 123). Yale Collection of American Literature, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
Scope and Contents
The Eugene Winick papers relating to Eugene O'Neill consist of correspondence and other papers dating from the mid 1920s through late 1940s. There is correspondence addressed to Eugene and Carlotta O'Neill from publishers, literary agents, law firms, and others, with large files for the literary agency, Richard J. Madden Play Company, Random House, Theatre Guild, and the law firm of Harry Weinberger. There are also subject folders for "foreign letters" and "requests" relating to permissions, translations, critical works and reception, research inquiries, financial matters, invitations, and other matters. Other papers consist chiefly of financial records, including income tax related material for the years from 1937 through 1948, investment reports, and royalty statements from Dramatists Play Service, Random House, and the Richard J. Madden Play Company.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Correspondence, 1923-1949. II. Other Papers, 1935-1949.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Dramatists -- United States -- 20th Century; O'Neill, Carlotta; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Weinberger, Harry, 1888-; Winick, Eugene; Dramatists Play Service (New York, N.Y.); Random House (Firm); Richard J. Madden Play Company; Theatre Guild
- Correspondence, 1923-1949; Series I; 2.92; (7 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. contains correspondence addressed to Eugene and Carlotta O'Neill from publishers, literary agents, law firms, and others dating from the 1920s through late 1940s. Large files can be found for the literary agency Richard J. Madden Play Company, Random House, Theatre Guild, and the law firm of Harry Weinberger. There are also subject folders for "foreign letters" and "requests" relating to permissions, translations, critical works and reception, research inquiries, financial matters, invitations, and other matters.
  Chiefly in English, with some material in French and Spanish.
  - A. and S. Lyons, Inc., 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Friends of France, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aronberg, W. E., 1946-1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Comarnescu, Petru, 1938-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dramatists Play Service, 1936-1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Federal Writers' Project, 1939 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ford, John, 1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Foreign letters", 1934-1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Frank, Bruno, 1943 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Frank, Waldo David, 1943 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Freedley, George, 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Galvao, Henrique, 1945 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Horace Liveright, Inc., 1923-1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - John H. G. Pell & Company, Inc., 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
  - "M" general, 1932-1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - McGinley, Arthur B., undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - McGrath, Jack, 1932-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Mirlas, León, 1934-1946 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Montrose, Ernst, 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1942 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Random House (Firm), 1935-1946 (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
  - "Requests", 1936-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 30-34)
  - Richard J. Madden Play Company, 1928-1933 (Box 2, Folder 35-40)
  - Richard J. Madden Play Company, 1931-1941 (Box 3, Folder 41-52)
  - Richard J. Madden Play Company, 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 53-60)
  - Sanborn, Ralph, 1933 January 28 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Simonson, Lee, 1932-1935, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Theatre Guild, 1933-1948, undated (Box 4, Folder 63-65)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1941 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Vanguard Press, 1942 November 30 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Weinberger, Harry, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Weinberger, Harry, 1933-1942 (Box 5, Folder 69-79)
  - Weinberger, Harry, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 80-81)
  - Young, Stark, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - ----, Phil, 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Others, 1932-1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 84)
- Other Papers, 1935-1949; Series II; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by material type.
  Series II. Other Papers consists chiefly of financial records, including income tax related material for the years from 1937 through 1948, investment reports, and royalty statements from Dramatists Play Service, Random House, and the Richard J. Madden Play Company.
  Chiefly in English, with some material in Italian and German.
  - Clippings, 1937-1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Foreign accounts, 1939-1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 86-87)
  - Income taxes, 1936-1949 (Box 6, Folder 88-96)
  - Investment reports, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 97-99)
  - Investment reports, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 100-101)
  - Royalty statements, 1935-1949 (Box 7, Folder 102-118)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 1 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Box 1, folder 10 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Box 1, folder 16 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Box 2, folder 27 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Box 2, folder 28 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Box 2, folder 29 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Box 2, folder 30 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Box 2, folder 31 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Box 2, folder 32 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Box 2, folder 33 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Box 2, folder 34 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Box 2, folder 35 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Box 3, folder 41 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Box 3, folder 42 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Box 3, folder 43 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Box 3, folder 44 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Box 3, folder 45 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Box 3, folder 46 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Box 3, folder 47 (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - Box 3, folder 48 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Box 3, folder 49 (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Box 3, folder 50 (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - Box 3, folder 51 (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Box 3, folder 52 (Box 8, Folder 142)
  - Box 4, folder 53 (Box 8, Folder 143)
  - Box 4, folder 54 (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - Box 4, folder 56 (Box 8, Folder 145)
  - Box 4, folder 57 (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - Box 4, folder 62 (Box 8, Folder 147)
  - Box 4, folder 63 (Box 8, Folder 148)
  - Box 4, folder 64 (Box 8, Folder 149)
  - Box 5, folder 69 (Box 8, Folder 150)
  - Box 5, folder 72 (Box 8, Folder 151)
  - Box 5, folder 74 (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - Box 5, folder 76 (Box 8, Folder 153)
  - Box 5, folder 77 (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - Box 5, folder 79 (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - Box 6, folder 80 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - Box 6, folder 81 (Box 8, Folder 157)